Michol Gaines

Cordele, GA 31015 micholgaines9_zt4@indeedemail.com 229-805-2031

Experienced Office Manager/Bookkeeper (including data entry) with a demonstrated history of working in the consumer goods/Manufacturing industry. Skilled in Payroll (including ADP) Account Reconciliation, Accounting, Accounts Payable, Accounts Receivable and Manufacturing. Strong administrative professional with a Diploma focused in Accounting and Finance from Meadows College of Business.

#readytowork

Work Experience

Bookkeeper

Mil-Spec Packaging - Macon, GA November 2019 to Present

Full Charge Bookkeeper

• Comprehensive knowledge of accounting and auditing principles, A/P, A/R, payroll, general ledger postings, invoicing, month end.

Collecting on delinquent accounts for two companies

- Reconcile multiple bank statements
- Filed Monthly/Quarterly Sales Tax
- Filed Annual Property Tax Return
- Compiled weekly cash flow report
- Processed Government payments
- Familiar with Peachtree (Sage 50), Microsoft Excel, Word, Outlook

Accounts Payable -Temporary position through Accountemps of Macon, Ga

Data Entry

Suez/Accountemps

August 2019 to October 2019

- Assisted with reconciling bills (credit cards, freight, etc.)
- Assisted with commission payments
- Accounts Payable checks
- Familiar with Oracle, Microsoft Office, Excel

Office Manager/Bookkeeper

APT Advanced Trailer & Equipment June 2005 to December 2018

Managed day to day tasks of office -Assistant to Plant Manager & President of company.

• Managed general office operations including all AP & AR bookkeeping, payroll processing, monitoring of deposits.

- Updated and reconciled AP, bank accounts
- Contacted customers to collect outstanding payments, processed payments
- Filed Monthly/Quarterly Sales Tax Reports
- Managed all HR including implementing Employee Manual, oversaw all worker's compensation issues, assisted plant manager/supervisors with all HR issues
- Proficient in Quickbooks, Microsoft Word, Excel
- Implemented and oversaw all cash/petty cash transactions along with reconciliation
- Implemented production report for plant manager

Tax Preparer-Temporary

Suez/Accountemps - Macon, GA January 2005 to February 2005

- Completed Advanced course in preparing public personal taxes
- Assisting Clients in completing their personal taxes
- Assisting Receptionist in answering telephone and any questions clients may have.

Receptionist

Suez/Accountemps - Macon, GA November 2004 to December 2004

- Assisted in Accounts Payable department, including processing invoices with their proper purchase orders and back-up.
- Distributed mail
- Typing miscellaneous reports for Controller
- · Assisting Accounts Payable with month end
- Answering multi-line telephone
- Fami with Windows 2000, Microsoft excel, word, outlook, access, online accounting system (Trans4M)

Bookkeeper

Tremont Produce

September 2002 to April 2003

Managed/Implemented day to day tasks of office/bookkeeping responsibilities

- Organized office for seasonal employer
- Created a filing system for AP, payroll, general ledger, AR, bank accounts
- Implemented office procedures for upcoming season
- Created customized invoices, credit memos, purchase orders
- Created weekly cash flow report for owner
- Familiar with all aspects of AP, AR, payroll (endo of month & end of year)
- Familiar with Quickbooks Pro, Microsoft office, word, excel, scanners

Bookkeeper

Pinehill Nursing Center 2000 to 2002

Medical billing/bookkeeper

- Reorganized and implemented AP payment and month end schedule for two facilities
- Created weekly cash flow report for administrator/owner
- Implemented computer for reconciliation of six bank statement
- Familiar with all aspects of AR (billing Medicare, Medicaid, collecting on accounts, month end closings)

- · Managed residents monies and petty cash
- Ste-up new company's AP, payroll, general ledger on Quickbooks Pro
- Familiar with Healthtech, Window 98, Quickbooks Pro programs

Bookkeeper

Engine Distributors 1998 to 2000

Bookkeeper

- · Organized and set-up new bookkeeping office for General Ledger, AP, AR and payroll
- Familiar with all aspects of payroll (including taxes, processing payroll, reconciling bank statement)
- Familiar with all aspects of General Ledger (including balancing of accounts, financial statements, month end closings, reconciling bank statements)
- Familiar with all aspects of Accounts Payable (including month and year end)
- Familiar with all aspects of Accounts Receivable (including month and year end, collecting on accounts)
- Completing and filing quarterly reports
- Familiar with inventory procedures and data entry (including month and year end
- Familiar with AS400 and Window 98 programs

Education

DIPLOMA in NAME

Meadows College of Business

1991 to 1992

Skills

- Full charge bookkeeper
- Quickbooks
- Microsoft Windows
- Microsoft Office
- Microsoft Word
- Microsoft Excel
- AS400
- Healthtech
- Data entry
- Sage 50
- Bill.com

Links

http://www.linkedin.com/in/mrgaines